<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Hassan Mish'al Junaid</title><link>https://Mishal.pm/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Hassan Mish'al Junaid</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Mishal.pm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My AI and Web Development Journey</title><link>https://Mishal.pm/posts/my-ai-and-web-development-journey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Mishal.pm/posts/my-ai-and-web-development-journey/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-ai-and-web-development-journey">&lt;strong>My AI and Web Development Journey&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently embarked on an exciting journey into AI and web development, leveraging my experience as a product manager at Ooredoo to explore new technical frontiers. Having successfully managed digital products and led cross-functional teams throughout my career, I&amp;rsquo;m now building the technical skills to complement my business expertise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beginning-from-product-management-to-code">&lt;strong>The Beginning: From Product Management to Code&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My background in managing digital content and new verticals at Ooredoo gave me firsthand exposure to technology implementation, but always from the business side. I worked extensively with development teams on product specifications, feature prioritization, and user testing, which sparked my curiosity about the technical underpinnings of these digital products.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://Mishal.pm/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Mishal.pm/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong>Hassan Mishal Junaid&lt;/strong> ðŸ‘‹&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am a &lt;strong>Product Development Manager&lt;/strong> with &lt;strong>6+ years&lt;/strong> of experience specializing in &lt;strong>Digital Product Strategy, Content Portfolio Management, and AI Implementation&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="professional-background">Professional Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with various organizations including &lt;strong>Ooredoo Maldives&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Ministry of Fisheries, Marine Resources &amp;amp; Agriculture (MOFMRA)&lt;/strong>, where I contributed to projects that launched innovative digital products, established strategic partnerships, and delivered measurable growth in customer engagement and revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My expertise includes:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Achievements</title><link>https://Mishal.pm/achievements/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Mishal.pm/achievements/</guid><description>&lt;p>ðŸ† Personal Achievements ðŸ†&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ðŸŽ“ Academic Excellence&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Graduated with &lt;strong>First Class Honors&lt;/strong> (3.91 CGPA) in Business Management with Marketing from University of West England ðŸŽ¯&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Currently pursuing &lt;strong>Masters in Business Analytics&lt;/strong> at Sunway University, Malaysia ðŸ“š&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed &lt;strong>PAL leadership program&lt;/strong> at Villa College ðŸš€&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>ðŸ… Professional Recognition&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Recipient of the prestigious &lt;strong>Digital Hero Award&lt;/strong> at Ooredoo Maldives for exceptional contributions to digital initiatives ðŸ’»&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Won the &lt;strong>Business Idea Award&lt;/strong> for innovative solution development ðŸ’¡&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Successfully organized the &lt;strong>Ooredoo Nation Gamers&amp;rsquo; Festival 2023&lt;/strong>, bringing together gaming enthusiasts across the Maldives ðŸŽ®&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Launched multiple &lt;strong>successful partnerships&lt;/strong> that significantly increased customer engagement KPIs ðŸ¤&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>ðŸš€ Project Successes&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telco Churn Prediction</title><link>https://Mishal.pm/posts/telco-churn-prediction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Mishal.pm/posts/telco-churn-prediction/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-i-built-a-customer-churn-prediction-app-for-telecom-companies">&lt;strong>How I Built a Customer Churn Prediction App for Telecom Companies&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I recently completed a fascinating project for my AI and Decision Making course in my Master of Business Analytics program, and I wanted to share this journey with you all. Our team tackled a real-world business problem: customer churn in the telecommunications industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge-predicting-who">&lt;strong>The Challenge: Predicting Who&amp;rsquo;s About to Leave&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Telecom companies face a constant battle to retain customers in today&amp;rsquo;s competitive market. Did you know that acquiring new customers costs significantly more than retaining existing ones? This makes identifying customers at risk of leaving (churning) incredibly valuable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>